why uh sovet Union to capture Latvia
а зачем ээ sovet Union захватить Латвия
Lithuania Estonia Finland
Литва Эстония финландия
but because these states
а потому что эти государства ранее
were previously part of the Russian
входили в состав Российской
Empire Okay uh part of Poland was also
империи О'кей э часть Польша тоже
once part of the Russian Empire
когда-то входил в часть rusian Empire
What does the Russian Empire have to do with it if it
Причём тут Российская империя если её
no longer exists There is a sovet Union there are other
уже нет Есть sovet Union есть другие
cities  and and
города и и
countries you work in Mosco
страны вы работать в Моско
who
кем
A I don't
А I don't
Work I don't work
Work Я не работаю
And how do you live
А как вы жить
a From My family
а From My family
uh you uh
ээ вас
wife pays
ээ платит жена
My How old are you
My Сколько тебе лет
And me in
А мне во
you to deceive you are an adult man
на ты обманывать ты взрослый мужчина
Okay 18 years old yes
Окей 18 лет да
yes For whom  iti
да На кого ити
study
учиться
tiche
тиче
tiche his his Oh I
тиче his his О я
this as in Russian
этот как по-русски
uh at the faculty at the university
ээ на факультет в университет
I teach history
преподаю историю
about the
о
teacher teacher teacher I am a
преподаватель преподаватель е Я
teacher of History at the University
преподаватель of History in University
of
of
sacr what period of history do you
sacr какой какой период стори Тебе
like and I
нравится а я больше
prefer the period of the 20th
люблю период XX
century the 10th century is very  there are many
века X век это очень много
events there is the first world war the second
события есть первый мировой войн Второй
world war
мировой войн
there is the
есть
interwar
межвоенный
period What exactly
период Что именно тебя
interests you I prefer the period of the
интересовать я больше люблю период
second world war
Второй мировой войны
Okay how do you
Окей как у вас
teach
учить
Why did the Soviet Union together with Hitler
Почему sovet Union вместе с Гитлер
attack Poland
напасть на Польша
for defense in order to prevent a
для обороны чтобы не допустить
premature attack by
преждевременного нападения
Germany and protect the local
Германии и защитить местный
people what  local people If you
народ какой местный народ Если вы
attack Poland together with Hitler and
напасть на Польша вместе с Гитлер и
tear Poland into two parts One
разорвать Польша на две части Одна
Hitler is the other
Гитлер другой
USSR if you look at the history of what
СССР если посмотреть на историю того что
they did,
делани
that is,
то есть
the Holocaust and other murders,
холокост и другие убийства
then this did not happen in the USSR That is, they
то в СССР такого не было То есть
protected the local population from this And
защитили от этого местное население А
then created another  the state, that is,
после создали другое государство то есть
well, they released Poland stop stop in the
ну выпустили Польше стоп стоп в
USSR there were con camps
СССР был кон лагери
in if the USSR had not attacked Poland and
в если бы СССР не напасть на Польша и
it would capture Polish soldiers take them
она захватить польские солдаты взять их
prisoner the USSR shot at Katyn
в плен СССР расстрел под Катынь
look and When Poland would fight against
посмотреть и Когда Польша воевать против
Hitler Soviet Union Yunin attack Poland with
Гитлер совт юнин напасть на Польша с
another blow in  dog or in the back in the back
другой удар в псину или в спину в спину
stab in the back Poland And if it weren’t for this
удар в спину Польша И если бы не этот
blow, but rather the
удар а наоборот
USSR help Poland together with England
СССР помочь Польша вместе с Англия
France there would not have been a capture of the
Франция не было бы захвата
SR I want to notify you about the PPP I am not the SR
СР хочу вас уведомить о том ППП я не СР
SR
СР
it is with us We are not
это у нас Мы не
with Mr. here is Mr. Mister  oh we have an
с мистер вот мистер мистер о у нас
insult if
оскорбление если
you say
говорить
France you can say nothing Nima
Франция можно сказать ничего не Нима
when Germany nada nal
когда Германия нада наль
standing like in the First World
стоя как на Первой мировой
War
войне
understand
understand
I
я
understand that Where did that come from in your
understand что Откуда это у тебя в
head that
голова что
helped Poland attacked her took part of her
помог Польша напал на неё забрал часть у
together with Hitler to make a parade in Brest you
вместе с Гитлер сделать парад в Брест ты
know  that Hitler will capture
знает что Гитлер захватит
Brest now this is
Брест сейчас это
Belarus and make a joint parade
Белорусь и сделать совместный парад
sovet Ar
sovet Ар
and german Army and give Brest to the Soviet
и german Army и Брест отдать Советский
Union
Союз
understand
understand
Yes a lot of
Yes много
time Sorry a lot of time
времени Извините много времени
This is history Let's
Это история Давай интересно
talk interestingly I can't say anything why is
говорить я не могу ничего сказать почему
this history think let's History is
это история думать давай История - это
Ana you should take  facts take the document
Ана ты должен брать факты брать докумен
and think think and make
и думать думать и делать
an interpretation Well, look
интерпретация Ну смотрите
in 1939 when the USSR and
в тридцать девятом году когда СССР и
Hitler attacked Poland and the USSR was not
Гитлер напали на Польшу а ССР не был
so ready for a war with Germany
настолько готов к войне с Германией
to help Poland
чтобы помочь Польше
[music]
[музыка]
about the Soviet Union
о Советский Союз
sell Aron to
продавать Арон в
Germany and after the attack on Poland
Германия и после нападения на Польша
And there was temporary
А было временное
cooperation in order to have time to
сотрудничества для того чтобы успеть
prepare for
подготовиться к
war,
войне
they almost managed to
успели чуть не совсем
J Okay uh
J Окей э А
Why did the Soviet Union capture Latvia Lithuania
зачем sovet Union захватить Латвия Литва
Estonia Finland
Эстония финландия
but because these states
а потому что эти государства ранее
were previously part of the Russian
входили в состав Российской
Empire
империи
Okay part of Poland was also once
Окей часть Польша тоже когда-то входил в
part of the R ire  What does the Russian
часть R ire Причём тут Российская
Empire have to do with it if it no longer exists? There is a Soviet Union,
империя если её уже нет Есть sovet Union
there are other cities and
есть другие города и
countries. I haven’t fully studied this matter yet,
страны Я ещё не до конца изучил это дело
so I can’t say much. Okay.
поэтому Мало чего смогу сказать О'кей А
How do you think it’s possible to attack
как ты считать можно ли нападать на
another country? If it was once part
другой страна Если она когда-то входила
of which  -the empire
в какой-то империя
depends on the
смотря в зависимости от
situation, for example, where you can attack.
ситуации например гда можно нападать А
And for example, And when there is an inconvenient
А когда там неудобное
government, inconvenient, like a
правительство неудобный это Как
government,
правительство го
inconvenient, aggressive,
неудобный агрессивная
Niriya, an example, just an
ирия пример просто
example, you can give this eml in
пример можешь этот эмл на
real life.
реальном
And I can give this example in
А могу этот пример привести на
modern times. Oh, and for example,
современных днях Ой а например
since 2014  years, the Ukrainian government very
вот с 2014 года украинская власть очень
aggressively tried to
агрессивно пыталась
annex
присоединить
Donbass
Донбасс
back and
обратно and
Ukraine came to That is, it already
Украина пришла к То есть она уже
hated
ненавидела
the Russians and forbade people to speak their
русских и запрещала людям говорить на их
language, that is, only Ukrainian throughout the
языке то есть только украински по всей
territory
территории
understand I think this is
understand я думать это
[music]
[музыка]
a lie, look in Russia 196
ложь смотрите в России 196
nationalities
национальностей
You have  I teach Nation of
У вас есть я учить Nation of
R there 5 milon
R там 5 milon
lives in Sha 5
живёт в ша 5
Miln you don’t have a single
Милн у вас нет ни один
Ukrainian and well, we don’t prohibit speaking
украино а ну мы не запрещаем говорить на
their
их
language in also don’t prohibit and in be a
языке в тоже не запрещать и в быть
Russian school in be a Russian school in my
русски школа в быть русски школа в мой
Sacramento there is a Russian community there there is
Сакраменто есть русский община там есть
there
там
there is n Natasha is from Kharkov, she studies in
есть н Наташа с Харькова она учится в
Russian-language schools She says Nobody
русскоязычных школах Она говорит Никто
forbids
не запрещает
Russian and then in the 2nd year a
русский а потом в 2 второй год прилетать
Russian rocket will fly in and smash her
русския ракета и разбить её
house How so
дом Как так
Well, if there had been some
Ну если бы была бы Причина какая-то
other reason, for example, that’s why then
другая например вот почему бы тогда
why would they rebel if they  They didn’t ban
почему восстали если они не Запрещали
Why the DPR People’s Republic
Почему ДНР НР
rebelled dnn this
восстали днн это
ration It’s like km mi this is the capture of the Russian
ration Это как км ми это захват русские
troops go this is to find out everything Bo shoot down the
войска го это узнать все Bo сбить
Malaysian R
малайзийский R
TR this is all It is
TR это всё
proven in the Crimea there was no capture it was
Доказано в Крыму не было захвата его
signed by people chose to join there is no life
подписали люди выбрали присоедини не быт
capture to see the transfer of
захват посмотреть переброс н
troops through the Kerch Strait
войско через Керченский пролив
and  capture
и захват
airports Crimea capture
аэропорты Крым захват
military unit Crimea capture
воинский часть Крым захват
Admin Build Crimea on the night of 26 to
Admin Build Крым в ночь с 26 на
27 February
27 февруари
was the occupation of Crimea and Putin even
год был оккупация Крыма и Путин даже
later said that we worked very
потом говорил что мы сработали очень
quickly our Green Man The green man
быстро наши Green Man Зелёный человечек
came and did everything he came and carried out the
пришёл и всё сделал он и пришёл и силой
occupation there by force  and now in I
провести там оккупация и сейчас в я
watch Telegram and YouTube When in Miya
смотреть Telegram и YouTube Когда в Мия
someone
кто-то
sings and
петь
arrest him and in the basement it’s like that,
н его арестовать и на подвал это так
look at the girls of Yalta sing in sish and
посмотреть девушки Ялта петь на сиш и их
arrest them for a Ukrainian song This
арестовать за украинская песня Это
is
это
understand
understand
Yes you can name you say that in R
Да ты можешь назвать ты сказать что в R
how much nationality
сколько nationality
almost oh, name me at least one school where they
почти ой назвать мне хоть один школа где
teach not in Russian but in the language of
преподавать не на русский язык а на язык
this nationality there is no such
этот национальность нет такой
school because the main language is Russian
школа потому что основной язык русский
they can study their language inside this school
они могут внутри этой школы изучать свой
there you study two lessons a week your
там ты изучать два урока в неделя свой
language and mathematics and chemistry everything is in Russian
язык а математика химия всё на русский
like that  question If in Ukraine there is life and
так вопрос Если в Украина быт и
Ukrainian school and Russian school Russian
украинский школа и русский школа русский
language School And in Russia there is only Russian language
язык Школа А в Раша только русский язык
School then where
Школа то где
understand
understand
Yes you know I still have little experience and
Yes знаете у меня ещё мало опыта и
knowledge I can’t
знаний не могу ничего
say anything Okay
сказать О'кей
[laughter]
[смех]
I’m I’m
я я
trimavsya damn it I’m not a cob
тримався блин я початок не
recorded the cob Without recording, I entered
записал початок Не записав вступив я в
California to study Russian for 2 years and pom everything is
калифор учить 2 года русский а пом всё
so hto lak piska komen write nay
так хто лак писка комен пись най
Telegram right at once he
Telegram прям зараз он
pok tse even more and more respectfully YouTube taking
пок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through SRR to the new ban and even more richly I
нас через срр в ньй бан и дуже багато
don’t show people the video right now I don’t show it
вдео не показую людям вчасно не показуе
information about stream Tomu for this purpose shob
информация про стрими Тому для того щоб
mi Mali operational link to write
ми Мали оперативний звязок пишиться
directly at the same time and while there in telegra okm
прямо зараз а пок там в телегра окм
video tezh va and korisna information and pon
видео теж ва и корисна информация и пон
va mati postiyny operational link
ва мати постийний оперативный звязок
nezalezhno VD togo chi show you about it
незалежно ВД того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
pipis L
пидпись L